Finding aid to the James Parker records, 1924-2005 Archives.Parker.1
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives
- Series I. Research, 1912-1997, n.d.; 31.0 Linear feet (72 boxes, 839 folders)
  - Subseries I.A. Card File, 1922-1933, 1943-1950, 1957-1996, n.d.; 25.0 Linear feet (60 boxes, 722 folders)
    - Dealers. French (A - G). (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Dealers. French (H - V). (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Dealers. French. 20th century. (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Mixed. Contains correspondence from Henry Sorensen (1968) and Kees Kooper (1989).
    - Dealers. German. (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Note: Contains correspondence from L. Bernheimer to Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1929), from v. Bielitzky, Kunsthandel D. Mendelsohn (1990) and Thomas Poller (1990).
    - Dealers. Italian. (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Note: Contains correspondence to Signor Dani Ghigo, Antichità (1980).
    - Dealers. P - S. (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Polish. Russian. Scottish. Swedish. Swiss. Contains correspondence from William Hardie (1991).
    - Dealers. U.S.A. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Dealers. U.S.A. (A - B). (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Dealers. U.S.A. (C - D). (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Dealers. U.S.A. (E - H). (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Dealers. U.S.A. (I - M). (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Robin Miller (1990).
    - Dealers. U.S.A. (N - Z). (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Neville K. Gay, Parenteau Studios (1990) and Guy Wildenstein, Wildenstein and Co., Inc. (1990).
    - Decorative arts. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Danish. Dutch. English. French. German. Italian. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss.
    - Dictionaries and directories. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Belgian. Dutch. English. French. German and Austrian. Italian. Russian. Swedish. U.S.A. Contains memorandum from Edith Galaska, M.M.A. (1991).
    - Dollhouses. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Enamels. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Chinese. English. French. German. Russian.
    - Exhibitions. A - D. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Canadian. Danish. Dutch.
    - Exhibitions. English. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Exhibitions. French. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Exhibitions. G - U. (Box 17, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes German. Italian. Japanese. Norwegian. Portuguese. Russian. Swedish. U.S.A.
    - Exports. (Box 17, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Fakes.
    - Frames. A - D. (Box 17, Folder 14)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Chinese. Dutch. Contains correspondence from Walter Jamieson, Jr. to Olga Raggio, M.M.A. (1979) and from Crispin Robinson, Arnold Wiggings and Sons, Limited (1990).
    - Frames. English. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Frames. French. (Box 17, Folder 16)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Anthony G. Victoria, Frederick P. Victoria and Son, Inc. (1983) and Christian Baulez, Musée National du Chateau de Versailles (1984).
    - Frames. G - U. (Box 17, Folder 17)
      Note: Includes German. Italian. Spanish. Swedish. U.S.A.
    - Furniture. A. (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes African. Australian. Austrian (18th century, Biedermeier, late 19th century, modern).
    - Furniture. B. (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Bamboo. Belgian. Bermuda. Contains correspondence from Joseph J. Dodge, Cummer Gallery of Art (1970).
    - Furniture. C. (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Canadian. Chinese (chairs, sofas). Czechoslovakian.
    - Furniture. Danish. (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Folk furniture.
    - Furniture. Dutch (1 of 5). (Box 18, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Beds. Benches. Contains correspondence to Mrs. Henry Weigl (1980).
    - Furniture. Dutch (2 of 5). (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Includes Cabinets.
    - Furniture. Dutch (3 of 5). (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Contains correspondence from Preston Remington, M.M.A. to S.L.H. Hazard (1926). Contains 1 photograph.
    - Furniture. Dutch (4 of 5). (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Commodes. Cradles. Desks. Foot warmers.
    - Furniture. Dutch (5 of 5). (Box 18, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Presses. Stools. Tables. Mixed. 19th century.
    - Furniture. Egyptian. (Box 18, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Sphinxes. Contains correspondence from George Kosseim (1975).
    - Furniture. English. Elizabethan (16th century). (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Beds. Chairs. Cupboards. Desks. Dressers. Tables. Contains correspondence with E.G. McGown (1971).
    - Furniture. English. Charles II and William and Mary (17th century). (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Beds. Cabinets. Chairs. Chests. Desks. Mirrors. Stools. Tables.
    - Furniture. English. Queen Anne - Chippendale (1 of 2). (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Beds. Bookcases. Cabinets. Chairs.
    - Furniture. English. Queen Anne - Chippendale (2 of 2). (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Chests. Desks. Mirrors. Settees. Wine coolers.
    - Furniture. English. Chippendale (1 of 4). (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Beds. Bookcases. Cabinets.
    - Furniture. English. Chippendale (2 of 4). (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Chairs.
    - Furniture. English. Chippendale (3 of 4). (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Chests. Commodes. Desks. Mirrors.
    - Furniture. English. Chippendale (4 of 4). (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Sofas. Stools. Tables. Wardrobes.
    - Furniture. English. Adam (1 of 6). (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Note: Contains M.M.A. memorandum from Colin Streeter to Elizabeth R. Usher (1971).
    - Furniture. English. Adam (2 of 6). (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Beds. Bookcases. Cabinets. Contains correspondence from Bearnes and Waycotts (1974).
    - Furniture. English. Adam (3 of 6). (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Furniture. English. Adam (4 of 6). (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Commodes.
    - Furniture. English. Adam (5 of 6). (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Corner cabinets. Mirrors. Pedestals and urns. Sofas.
    - Furniture. English. Adam (6 of 6). (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Tables. Wine coolers. Mixed.
    - Furniture. English. Regency (1 of 3). (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Furniture. English. Regency (2 of 3). (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Commodes. Cradles. Desks.
    - Furniture. English. Regency (3 of 3). (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Mirrors. Sofas. Stools. Tables. Thrones. Wine coolers. Mixed.
    - Furniture. English. Victorian. (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Beds. Bookcases. Cabinets. Chairs. Commodes. Cradles. Desks. Sofas and settees. Stools. Tables. Contains correspondence from Barry L. Shifman, Indianapolis Museum of Art (1991).
    - Furniture. English. Welsh. (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Modern and reproductions.
    - Furniture. Finnish. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Furniture. French. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Furniture. French. Renaissance - Louis XIII. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Beds. Cabinets. Chairs. Chests. Makers. Materials and motifs. Mixed. 19th century Renaissance style. Panels. Stools. Tables.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XIII. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Note: Contains correspondence and photograph from Reverend Cletus A. Miller, Church of the Annunciation, Cincinnati, OH (1969).
    - Furniture. French. Louis XIV (1 of 4). (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Armoires. Beds. Cabinets.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XIV (2 of 4). (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Clocks. Commodes. Daybeds. Desks. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XIV (3 of 4). (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Meuble d'appui. Mirrors. Pedestals. Settees. Stools.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XIV (4 of 4). (Box 21, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Tables. Thrones. Makers. Contains 1 slide.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Lighting. French for torchères.
    - Furniture. French. Régence. (Box 21, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Armoires. Bookcases. Beds. Cabinets. Chairs. Coffers. Commodes. Desks. Pedestals. Sofas. Tables. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Régence (Cressent). (Box 21, Folder 9)
      Note: Cressent, Charles, 1685-1768. Includes Armoires. Bookcases. Cabinets. Commodes. Desks. Encoignures. Medal cabinets. Pedestals. Mixed and miscellaneous. Tables. Contains 3 slides.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV (1 of 6). (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Armoires. Beds. Bookcases. Bureau de dame. Cabinets. Chairs. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV (2 of 6). (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Coffers on stands. Commodes.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV (3 of 6). (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Desks. Encoignures.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV (4 of 6). (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Settees. Stools. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV (5 of 6). (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Tables (console). Contains correspondence from Betsy Jean Rosasco (1971?). Contains 1 negative and 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV (6 of 6). (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Tables (dressing, gaming, miscellaneous, writing). Thrones. Other misc.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (A - B). (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Angot, Avisse, Barr, Bayer, Bernard, Bircklé, Boucault, Boudin, Boulard.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (Boulle) (1 of 5). (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Note: Boulle, André-Charles, 1642-1732. Includes Armoires. Bookcases. Cabinets. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (Boulle) (2 of 5). (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Candelabras. Chairs. Chests. Clocks. Coffers.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (Boulle) (3 of 5). (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Commodes. Cradles. Desks.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (Boulle) (4 of 5). (Box 22, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Lighting (gilt bronze wall brackets). Meuble d'appui. Pedestals.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (Boulle) (5 of 5). (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Tables. Mixed.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (B.V.R.B.). (Box 22, Folder 10)
      Note: Risenburgh, Bernard van, II (French ébéniste, after 1696-ca. 1766).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.B. General /f. B.V.R.B.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (C). (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Note: Cites - Carel, Charpentier, Chevallier, Cresson, Criaerd. Contains correspondence from French and Company, Inc. to Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1930). Contains 2 photographs and 1 rubbing.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (D). (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Note: Cites - Dautriche, Delorme, Demoulin, Desforges, Doirat, Dubois, Dubut, Dufour, Duhamel, Durand. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (E - F). (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - Ellaume, Falconet, Feilt, Felix, Feurstein, Flechy, Foliot, Foullet, Fromaceau.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (G - H). (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Garnier, Gaudreau, Genty, Gourdin, Hache, Hansen, Hedouin, Heurtaud, Holthausen.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (J). (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Jacob, Joseph, Joubert.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (L - M). (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Note: Cites - Lapié, Latz, Lebas, Leleu, L'Hermite, Lieutaud, Macret, Malle, Meunier, Mewesen, Michard, Migeon, Mondon.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (N - O). (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Nadal, Nogaret, Normand, Oeben.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (P - R). (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes R.V.L.C. [Roger Vandercruse called Lacroix]. Cites - Peridiez, Petit, Pineau, Pioniez, Pothier, Reizell, Remy, Reuze, Revault, Riesener, Roussel, Rubestuck.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (S - Z). (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Note: Cites - Saddon, Saint George, Saunier, Schmitz, Sené, Severin, Teuné, Topino, Tillard, Tuart, Wolff.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers (Various). (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI (1 of 6). (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI (2 of 6). (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI (3 of 6). (Box 23, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Commodes. Cradles. Desks.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Furniture. French. Louis XVI [4 of 6] for daybeds.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI (4 of 6). (Box 23, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Encoignures. Jardinières. Pedestals. Sofas.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI (5 of 6). (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Stools. Tables (sideboard, console).
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI (6 of 6). (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Tables (writing, gaming, misc. and mixed). Thrones.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (A - B). (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Avisse, Avril, Bauve, Benneman, Bircklé, Boichod, Boucault, Boudin, Boulard, Brizard, Bury, B.V.R.B.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (C). (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Canabas, Carpentier, Cosson, Cramer.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (Carlin). (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Note: Carlin, Martin (French master ébéniste, ca. 1739-1785, master 1766). Contains correspondence to Patricia Lemonnier (1978).
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (D). (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Dautriche, Delaisement, Delanois, Delaunay, Delorme, Demay, Denizot, Dester, Dubois, Dupain.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (E - G). (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Note: Cites - Evald, Feurstein, Foliot, Foullet, Garnier, Gilbert, Goudin, Grevenich. Contains 1 photograph.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (H - J). (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Note: Cites - Hericourt, Hervé, Heurtaut, Jacob, Joseph, Joubert, Julienne. Contains correspondence from Henry Sorensen (1973). Contains 1 photograph.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (K - L). (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Note: Cites - Kemp, Lacroix [R.V.L.C], Langdon, Legry, Lelarge, Leleu, Levasseur, Lieutaud.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (M). (Box 24, Folder 10)
      Note: Cites - Macret, Mauter, Molitor, Montigny, Moreau. Contains correspondence from Ulrich Leben (1985).
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (N - P). (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Note: Cites - Nadal, Oeben, Ohneberg. Pafrat, Palma, Petit, Pioniez.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (R). (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Note: Cites - Remy, Riesener, Roussel.
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (S). (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - Saunier, Schey, Schlichtig, Schmidt, Schmitz, Schneider, Schwerdfeger, Sené, Stockel.=
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (T). (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Teune, Tilliard, Topino. Contains correspondence from Henry Sorensen (1976).
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (V - W). (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Vassou, Weisweiler, Wolff. Contains correspondence from Patricia Lemonnier (1979).
    - Furniture. French. Louis XVI. Makers (Mixed). (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Furniture. French. Revolution. Directoire. Consulate. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Furniture. French. Empire (1 of 11). (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Armoires. Athéniennes. Beds.
    - Furniture. French. Empire (2 of 11). (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Cabinets.
    - Furniture. French. Empire (3 of 11). (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Furniture. French. Empire (4 of 11). (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Furniture. French. Empire (5 of 11). (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Commodes. Cradles.
    - Furniture. French. Empire (6 of 11). (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Desks.
    - Furniture. French. Empire (7 of 11). (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Jardinières. Pedestals. Sofas. Somnos.
    - Furniture. French. Empire (8 of 11). (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Stools. Contains correspondence with Christopher Monkhouse, Museum of Art, Rhode Island School of Design (1977).
    - Furniture. French. Empire (9 of 11). (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Tables (1 of 2).
    - Furniture. French. Empire (10 of 11). (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Tables (2 of 2).
    - Furniture. French. Empire (11 of 11). (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Thrones. Contains correspondence with Serge Grandjean, Musée du Louvre, and Henry Sorensen (1964).
    - Furniture. French. Empire. Makers. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      Note: Cites - Biennais, Bellangé, Desmalter, Lemarchand, Jacob, Youf. Contains correspondence from Peter Hill, United States Antiques Appraisals, to Berry Tracy, M.M.A. (1968).
    - Furniture. French. Restoration (1 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Beds. Cabinets. Chairs.
    - Furniture. French. Restoration (2 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Commodes. Cradles. Desks. Tables. Mixed.
    - Furniture. French. Second Empire (1 of 3). (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Furniture. French. Second Empire (2 of 3). (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Commodes. Desks.
    - Furniture. French. Second Empire (3 of 3). (Box 26, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Pedestals. Sofas. Stools. Tables.
    - Furniture. French. Second Empire. Makers. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Note: Cites - Beurdele, Christofle, Cruchet, Dasson, Durand, Fourdinois, Giroux, Grohé, Kreisser, Millet, Monbro, Sormani, Zwiener. Contains correspondence with Mrs. Raol D. Weigner (1969).
    - Furniture. French. Art Nouveau. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Furniture. French. Art Deco. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Furniture. French. Provincial. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Furniture. German. 16th - 17th centuries. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Includes Cabinets. Chairs. Chests. Tables.
    - Furniture. German. 18th century. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (1 of 7). (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (2 of 7). (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (3 of 7). (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Chests. Coffers. Commodes.
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (4 of 7). (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Cradles. Cupboards. Desks.
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (5 of 7). (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Pedestals. Sofas. Stools.
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (6 of 7). (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Tables.
    - Furniture. German. Rococo (7 of 7). (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Mixed.
    - Furniture. German. 19th century. (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Folk.
    - Furniture. German. Roentgen (1 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Note: Roentgen, Abraham, 1711-1793. Roentgen, David, 1743-1807.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.B. General / f. Roentgen.
    - Furniture. German. Roentgen (2 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Boxes. Cabinets. Chairs. Clocks. Coffers. Commodes.
    - Furniture. German. Roentgen (3 of 3) (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Desks. Panels. Tables. Mixed. Contains correspondence from Betsy Jean Rosasco (1977).
    - Furniture. Gr - H. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Greek. Hungarian.
    - Furniture. Indian. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Sandalwood. Contains correspondence from Amin Jaffer, Victoria and Albert Museum (1993) and to James L. Stoltzfus (1972).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Furniture. Chinese
    - Furniture. [Indo]. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Indo-Dutch. Indo-Portuguese.
    - Furniture. Irish. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Furniture. Italian. 15th - 17th centuries (1 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Furniture. Italian. 15th - 17th centuries (2 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Chests. Commodes. Cradles. Desks. Pedestals.
    - Furniture. Italian. 15th - 17th centuries (3 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Furniture. Italian. 17th - 18th centuries (1 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Louis XIV chairs.
    - Furniture. Italian. 17th - 18th centuries (2 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 14)
      Note: Includes Louis XV chairs. Contains 1 slide.
    - Furniture. Italian. 17th - 18th centuries (3 of 3). (Box 28, Folder 15)
      Note: Includes Louis XVI chairs. Contains memorandum to John Goldsmith Phillips, M.M.A. (1963) re: Report on the Cooper Union Project. Contains correspondence between W.R. Coe and Jacques Seligmann and Fils. (1922) and from Lorraine Gilligan, Planting Fields Foundation (1985).
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century (1 of 6). (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Beds. Benches. Cabinets.
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century (2 of 6). (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Chairs (portraits).
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century (3 of 6). (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Commodes. Cradles. Contains correspondence to Weston W. Thorn (1982).
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century (4 of 6). (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Desks. Pedestals. Prie-dieux. Settees and sofas. Stools.
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century (5 of 6). (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Tables (rococo).
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century (6 of 6). (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Tables (Louis XVI).
    - Furniture. Italian. 18th century. Makers. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Furniture. Italian. 19th century (1 of 4). (Box 29, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Beds. Benches. Bookcases. Bronze furniture. Cabinets. Contains correspondence with Esther and John Carroll (1990) and v. Bielitzky, Kunsthandel D. Mendelsohn (1990).
    - Furniture. Italian. 19th century (2 of 4). (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Contains correspondence from J. Jacqueline Gholizadeh (1984) and Reverend Denis P. Ferrigno, Cathedral of Saint Joseph, Hartford, CT (1980).
    - Furniture. Italian. 19th century (3 of 4). (Box 29, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Chests. Commodes. Cradles. Desks. Pedestals. Sofas.
    - Furniture. Italian. 19th century (4 of 4). (Box 29, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Sideboards. Stools. Tables.
    - Furniture. Italian. 19th century. Makers. (Box 29, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Mixed. Contains correspondence from v. Bielitzky, Kunsthandel D. Mendelsohn (1990).
    - Furniture. Italian. Art Nouveau - 20th century. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Furniture. J - N. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Jamaican. Japanese. Korean. Maltese. Mexican. New Zealand. Norwegian. Contains correspondence to Michael Cavallero Boccio (1991).
    - Furniture. P. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Painted. Polish. Portuguese (Robert C. Smith's articles, beds, cabinets, chairs and settees, commodes, mirrors, tables). Contains correspondence from Maria Helena Mendes Pinto, Museu Nacional de Arte Antiga (1972).
    - Furniture. Russian. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Beds. Cabinets. Chairs. Commodes. Desks. Tables. Heinrich Gambs. Mixed. Folk furniture. Contains correspondence to Robert E. Boyd, Jewelry and Gifts (1984) and from Dr. Anthony Netting (1978).
    - Furniture. Rustic. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Furniture. S - So. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Scottish. Silver (French). South American. Contains correspondence with Joan S. Brown (1979).
    - Furniture. Spanish. (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes 16th - 17th centuries (cabinets, seat furniture, tables). 18th century (beds, commodes, seat furniture, tables). 19th century (seat furniture). Contains correspondence with Pierre Uhart (1973).
    - Furniture. Sw. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Swedish (18th century cabinets, chairs; 19th century chairs, commodes, desks, mirrors, tables, table consoles; thrones; folk furniture). Swiss.
    - Furniture. Turkish. (Box 30, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Olana [Mansion]. Contains correspondence to Roy R. McLain (1971), Kenneth J. Botet (1970), Marie E. Cassetta (1974) and with Carl Brand (1974).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Ornament Prints. Turqueries.